

ERWIN IBARRA V.

APPIAN LEVEL 2 ENGINEER / .NET DEVELOPER / BPM / MBA WWW.ERWINIBARAV.COM

ABOUT

Born & raised in Saltillo, Mexico. Have a Computer Science bachelor's degree by National Technological Institute of Mexico, and a master's in business administration by TecMilenio University.

Along my 5 years of experience in technology I have had the opportunity to work in 3 different countries for some of the biggest consulting firms worldwide, impacting some of the most important companies around the globe on industries such as travel & communications, energy, and health & insurance. I have had the opportunity to work face to face with my clients to add them value during the entire software development life cycle. I have had the grace of training and growing teams.

Twice certified as Appian practitioner. Twice certified in Agile Methodologies and Certified in Project Management Methodologies. Focus on the use of effective code standards on all my endeavors. Have experience with Appian, C# and several technologies of Microsoft platform such as VB, VBA, T-SQL, WCF, WPF & Azure as well as MVC and other distributed architectures for software development.

BASIC INFO

Birthday: 30/06/1993

Birthplace: Saltillo, Mexico

Citizenship: Mexican

Current Location: Saltillo, Mexico

Preferred Location: US & MX

Web Site: www.ErwinlbarraV.com

Email: lam@ErwinlbarraV.com

Phone Number: +52 844 184 1332

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)

English (Proficient)

EDUCATION

MASTER'S IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

TEC MILENIO • JAN 2018 - DEC 2019

A master's in business administration program with major in quality and productivity and certification in project management methodologies

COMPUTER SYSTEMS ENGINEER

TECNM • JAN 2012 - DEC 2016

A computer science bachelor's degree with major in software development

SOFT SKILLS

- Planning
- Communication
- Teamwork
- Analytical Thinning
- Leadership



ERWIN IBARRA V.

APPIAN LEVEL 2 ENGINEER / .NET DEVELOPER / BPM / MBA WWW.ERWINIBARAV.COM

EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL LEAD / APPIAN COE LEAD

CECOACHING • SANTANDER BANK (MEXICO) • OCT 2020 - CURRENT

Development of BPM solutions for the Management and Monitoring department at the Risks area of the bank. This system includes multiple integrations with legacy systems and the automation in Appian of all the business processes required to manage and control an enterprise client of the bank. The application allows risk analysts to follow up the clients as well as change different scores of the clients based on its risks and liabilities as well as to manage the financial statements and all financial data of the client. Later, a risk committee approves or denies the changes performed by the analyst.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

HEXAWARE • SITA (UK) • JUL 2019 - OCT 2020

Development of a product for electronic visa for a UK client that includes the automation in Appian of all the business processes required to issue a visa such as immigration, security, and document check. The application allows a user to start a visa application from an integrated frontend in Drupal and provide all required evidence based on the requested visa type, later a group of security officers and visa officers continue the process in Appian till the electronic visa is finally issued.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

HEXAWARE • BPM LAB (INDIA) • JAN 2019 – JUN 2019

Working for Hexaware's BPM Lab designing innovative solutions such as an application for loan origination that includes all the steps from taking a loan application up to approve it and notify both borrowers and lenders through internal feeds. The application allows borrowers to take an application form, and then it is processed, evaluated and pre-approved or denied by the bank based on the inputs from the borrower.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Appian
- C#
- VB
- VBA
- ASP.NET
- MvSOL
- T-SOL
- Java
- WPF
- Rest API
- WCF
- Azure
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Windows
- Linux
- Time Management
- Problem Solving
- Strategic Thinking

AWARDS

HEXAWARE'S BEST DEBUTANT

2017

2ND HIGHEST SCORE OF BATCHES 2016



ERWIN IBARRA V.

APPIAN LEVEL 2 ENGINEER / .NET DEVELOPER / BPM / MBA WWW.ERWINIBARAV.COM

EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT ANALYST

ACCENTURE • INTEGRYS (MEXICO) • JAN 2018 - DEC 2018

A billing solution for energy companies was maintained and Certified SAFe® Agilist enhanced. The process is to resolve defects, extend the functionality of the same by adding new business requirements and migrate the SFPC whole legacy application from C++ to C#. Work alongside JUN 2020 Minneapolis functional team and product owners in close Scrum Foundation Professional collaboration to ensure the quality of the product.

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

HEXAWARE • AIG (MEXICO) • JAN 2016 - JUL 2017

Worked alongside Houston & Chennai teams for supporting and maintaining the entire set of enterprise solutions for human resources global department of an important health and insurance company. Bug-fixed, hot fixed and supported Appian applications such as employee performance management system, tuition reimbursement system, enterprise bus system as well as many other integrations with other enterprise solutions.

JUNIOR DEVELOPER

APTIV • TLL (MEXICO) • JUN 2015 - DEC 2015

We worked in the development of a production tracking system for important manufacturing client. We developed desktop and batch applications for tracking the state of single part number along the entire production process to allow the clients to be able to estimate the current state of the production plan.

CERTIFICATIONS

SAFE® AGILIST

JUN 2020

Certificate

APPIAN LEVEL 2

JAN 2021 & JUL 2019

Appian Practitioner Level 2

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

APR 2019

Project Management Methodologies based in PM Book certification

APPIAN ANALYST

MAR 2017

Appian Analyst Certified Practitioner

CONTESTS

APPIAN WORLD HACKATHON 2020

APPIAN WORLD HACKATHON

2019

HACKMTY

2015